Register of the Claire Sterling papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject file, 1960-1994 (Box 23-81)
  - Mafia, file 2 (Box 54-55)
    - Bono, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 54: 4)
    - Catanese/Catania, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 54: 5)
    - Drugs and terrorism, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 54: 6)
    - La Torre law, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 54: 7)
    - Liggio, Luciano, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 54: 8)
    - Masons, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 55: 1)
    - Terzo Livello (third level), 1984-1988 (Box-folder 55: 2)
  - Mafia, file 3 (Box 55)
    - Agrigento, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 55: 3)
    - Mafia and terrorism, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 55: 4)
    - Napoli, Enzo, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 55: 5)
    - Pizza Connection, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 55: 6)
  - Mafia, file 4, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 56: 1-3)
  - Mafioso by Servadio and Canada heroin trail, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 56: 4-5)
  - Mafioso by Servadio and Canada heroin trail (Contd.), 1974-1976 (Box-folder 57: 1)
  - Mastelloni, Carlo, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 57: 2-5)
  - Maxiprocesso and Falcone motivation, 1984, undated (Box-folder 57: 6)
    Also known as Maxi Trial
  - Maxiprocesso and Falcone motivation (Contd.), 1984, undated (Box-folder 58: 1-3)
  - Maxiprocesso testimony, Giornale de Sicilia, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 58: 4-5)
  - Maxiprocesso testimony, Giornale de Sicilia (Contd.), 1986-1987 (Box-folder 59: 1-4)
  - The Mob by Virgil Peterson and Rush to Judgement by Mark Lane, 1983, 1996 (Box-folder 59: 5-6)
  - The Mob by Virgil Peterson and Rush to Judgement by Mark Lane (Contd.), 1983, 1996 (Box-folder 60: 1)
  - Napoli family, file 1, 1977-1986 (Box-folder 60: 2-7)
    Includes coversheet for Thieves' World
  - Napoli family, file 2, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 61: 1-8)
  - Napoli, Cassará, and Epaminonda, 1982, 1985 (Box-folder 61: 9)
  - Napoli, Cassará, and Epaminonda (Contd.), 1982, 1985 (Box-folder 62: 1)
  - Narcotics reports, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 62: 2-5)
  - Narcotics reports, 1992 (Box-folder 63: 1)
  - NATO and communism, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 63: 2-5)
  - NATO and communism (Contd.), 1968-1976 (Box-folder 64: 1)
  - Negri, Toni, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 64: 2-3)
  - New terrorist wave, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 64: 4-5)
  - Organized crime, 1993 (Box-folder 64: 6)
  - Other gangs, international, 1984 (Box-folder 64: 7)
  - Palermo, Carlo (Box 64-65)
    - Palermo judgement, 1985, undated (Box-folder 64: 8-9)
    - Pizzolungo court judgement, 1985 (Box-folder 65: 1-4)
  - Palestine and terrorism, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 65: 5-6)
  - Palestinians, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 66: 1-6)
    Includes clippings on Carlos
  - Parretti, Giancarlo, 1991 (Box-folder 66: 7)
  - Pennsylvania Crime Commission reports, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 66: 8-9)
  - "Pizza" case, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 66: 10)
  - "Pizza" case (Contd.), 1984-1988 (Box-folder 67: 1-4)
  - Pizza connection, 1973-1986 (Box-folder 67: 5)
  - Poland, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 67: 6)
  - Post-Russia, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 68: 1-3)
  - Racketeer-influenced and corrupt organizations, 1979, undated (Box-folder 68: 4)
  - Russia (Box 68-69)
    - 1978-1980 (Box-folder 68: 5)
    - 1990-1992 (Box-folder 68: 6)
    - 1990-1993 (Box-folder 68: 7)
    - 1990-1993 (Contd.) (Box-folder 69: 1-2)
  - Scandinavia, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 69: 3)
  - Schengen Agreement, French Senate reports, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 69: 4-5)
  - Schengen Agreement, French Senate reports (Contd.), 1991-1994 (Box-folder 70: 1-5)
  - Schengen Agreement, French Senate reports (Contd.), 1991-1994 (Box-folder 71: 1)
  - Schengen Agreement, European Community/United Nations/Council of Europe conventions, and United Nations crime report, 1981-1992 (Box-folder 71: 2-5)
  - Secret services, east, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 72: 1)
  - Security deficit, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 72: 2)
  - Service de Documentation Extérieure et de Contre-Espionnage (SDECE), 1977 (Box-folder 72: 3)
  - Sicilian Mafia abroad, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 72: 4)
  - Sindona-Ambrosoli, Caló-Carboni, Caló-Rinivio, and Giudizo-drugs, 1985, undated (Box-folder 72: 5-7)
  - Singapore, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 72: 8)
  - Singapore (Contd.), 1968-1975 (Box-folder 73: 1)
  - Sources, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 73: 2)
  - Soviet Bloc complicity, 1990 (Box-folder 73: 3)
  - The Soviet Mafia by Arkady Vaksberg, undated (Box-folder 73: 4-6)
  - Soviet Union, 1992-1993, undated (Box-folder 73: 7)
  - Spain, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 73: 8-9)
  - Spain (Contd.), 1974-1979 (Box-folder 74: 1-3)
  - Spain, 1991 (Box-folder 74: 4)
  - Spatola indictment (Sciacchitano) and drugs/Catania, undated (Box-folder 74: 5-7)
  - Spatola indictment (Sciacchitano) and drugs/Catania (Contd.), undated (Box-folder 75: 1)
  - Suzdal, United Nations/USSR organized crime seminar, 1991 (Box-folder 75: 2-3)
  - Switzerland, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 75: 4)
  - Tarason, Artjom, and rubles, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 75: 5-7)
  - Terranova, Cesare judgement, undated (Box-folder 76: 1)
  - Terrorism (Box 76-78)
    - 1974-1982 (Box-folder 76: 2-3)
    - 1977-1980 (Box-folder 76: 4-6)
    - 1977-1980 (Contd.) (Box-folder 77: 1)
    - 1977-1981 (Box-folder 77: 2)
    - 1978-1979 (Box-folder 77: 3)
    - 1979-1982 (Box-folder 77: 4-5)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 77: 6)
    - 1986 (Contd.) (Box-folder 78: 1)
    - 1986-1988 (Box-folder 78: 2)
  - Terrorism in Palestine, Libya, and Ireland, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 78: 3-4)
  - Thatcher, Margaret and Britain, 1960, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 78: 5-7)
  - Thatcher, Margaret and Britain (Contd.), 1960, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 79: 1-4)
  - United Kingdom, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 79: 5)
  - United States, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 79: 6)
  - United States, Mexico, and Canada, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 79: 7)
  - United States position, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 79: 8)
  - United States position (Contd.), 1990-1992 (Box-folder 80: 1)
  - United States, Russia, and Yakusa, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 80: 2-4)
  - West Germany, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 80: 5-6)
  - West Germany (Contd.), 1977-1979 (Box-folder 81: 1)
  - World drug trade, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 81: 2)
  - Zaza interrogation, Rinvio Giudizio, Michelangelo Aiello, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 81: 3-6)
- Sound recordings, circa 1975-1993, undated (Box 82)
  Contains cassettes and reels arranged by format, then by date. Titles are transcribed from sound recording labels and may not reflect the contents of the tape.
  - Sound cassettes (Box 82-83)
    - Untitled, undated (Box-folder 82: 1)
    - Claire Sterling, undated (Box-folder 82: 2)
    - H-J Klein [Bach excerpts], undated (Box-folder 82: 3)
    - "La Maffia: Histoire d'un empire caché," Claire Sterling/Patricia Martin, undated (Box-folder 82: 4-6)
    - Leo and Krause, undated (Box-folder 82: 7)
    - Le Vien, undated (Box-folder 82: 8-11)
    - Operazione Leo, undated (Box-folder 82: 12)
    - Rita, undated (Box-folder 82: 13)
    - [ Der Spiegel] piece, undated (Box-folder 82: 14)
    - Tape VII, undated (Box-folder 82: 15)
    - VW scandal, undated (Box-folder 82: 16)
    - YLVA, NZZ, Winterthur, undated (Box-folder 82: 17)
    - NZZ tapes on P. Krause and Winterthur Trial, circa 1975 (Box-folder 82: 18)
    - Der Spiegel, 1977 August 15 (Box-folder 82: 19)
    - Tape 10, 1977 November 8-1977 November 16 (Box-folder 82: 20)
    - Tape 11 to 13, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 82: 21)
    - Portugal, Cossiga, 1978 October 24 (Box-folder 82: 22)
    - STARABBA-NZZ, 1978 October 25 (Box-folder 82: 23)
    - Barry Farber Show, 1981 May 7 (Box-folder 82: 24)
    - TG2 dossier, Lioggio and Greco, 1986 November 3 (Box-folder 82: 25)
    - La Vien, office, 1986 June 15 (Box-folder 82: 26)
    - Claire Sterling, tape 1 and 3, 1991 July (Box-folder 82: 27-28)
    - Claire Sterling, tape 4-6, possibly 1991 (Box-folder 82: 29-31)
    - Claire Sterling, 1991 Stepember 12 (Box-folder 82: 32)
    - Claire Sterling, 1991 December 18 (Box-folder 82: 33)
    - Claire Sterling, 1992 February (Box-folder 82: 34)
    - Chinese Mafia, 1992 August (Box-folder 82: 35)
    - Claire Sterling, 1992 August-Steptember (Box-folder 82: 36)
    - Claire Sterling, 1992 December (Box-folder 82: 37)
    - Claire Sterling, 1993 February (Box-folder 82: 38)
  - Sound tape reels (Box 82)
    - Untitled, undated (Box-folder 82: 39-40)
      Two sound tape reels
- Photographs, 1954-1982, undated (Box 83)
  Contains photographic prints and negatives of the Sterling family.
  - Photographic prints, 1954-1982, undated (Box-folder 83: 1-4)
  - Negatives, undated (Box-folder 83: 5)